

RELATED TECHNICAL SKILS

LANGUAGES

JAVA **KOTLIN**

DATABASES

MYSQL SQL

FRAMEWORKS

JAVAFX SWING

ARCHITECTURES

MVC MVVM 3 TIER

OTHER

WEB APIs GIT HUB/LAB **AGILE**

NON RELATED TECHNICAL SKILS

LANGUAGES TYPESCRIPT

PYTHON DART C++ C

DATABASES

PHP

FIREBASE

FRAMEWORKS

KOTLINFX FLUTTER **REACT**

UTHPALA D. LIYANAGE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - JAVA

BSc (Hons.) Computer Science & Software Engineering

ABOUT ME

I am a skilled, experienced Software Engineering Professional and having more than 4 years of software development experience in Desktop application development, Web - applications and Mobile application development with ability to perform and deliver in technically complex projects, meet deadlines and adaptable to ever-changing priorities with good communication with other team members. Loves to work in new solution oriented situations, think out of box and conduct Tech Talk Sessions to team mates who needs. Also doing out sourced projects since 2017 as a hobby.

WORK EXPERIENCE (4 YEARS +)

J2ee Software Engineer, Devzone.lk

December 2019 – Present

Full Stack J2EE Desktop & Web Applications – Java

J2ee Software Engineer – Associate, Devzone.lk

November 2018 - December 2019

Full Stack J2EE developer on Web Applications & Desktop **Applications**

PROJECTS - IN CAREER

XENON PHARMACY POS (JAN 2021 - PRESENT)

XENON PHARMACY POS is a commercial type Point of Sales System product introduced by Devzone for the Pharmacies in Sri Lanka. The System consist with a Standalone Desktop Application using Java + Kotlin, MVVM with a spring boot server and a Web Analytical Tool Application with React, Php and Python. This system is capable to handle 50 Terminals at a time without overloading by load balancer.

Contribution:

- Developed and introduced new Application Loader to handle bulk of data from database to user interface with minimum latency using java threads by replacing existing one.
- Contributed on Code Reviews of other Associate developers and Interns.
- Contributed in Bug Ticket Resolving.
- Developed Automatic Bill Saving system at the Cashier panel of the application.
- Developed "Xenon Network Manager" which handles application's network and terminal connections.
- Developed Billing Cart of the Application.
- Contributed in "Xenon Log & Error Manager"
- Contributed in "Xenon License Manager" to register application on windows registry.
- Contributed in development of Stock and Inventory Management Function.
- Contributed in Application UI development with JavaFX

TOOLS & IDEs

- **❖ INTELLIJ IDEA**
- ❖ VS CODE
- ❖ VISUAL STUDIO
- **❖ ANDROID STUDIO**
- **❖ NETBEANS**
- **❖** ECLIPSE
- **❖** GOOGLE COLAB
- ❖ PHP STORM
- **❖** WEB STROM
- ❖ POSTMAN
- **❖** SCENE BUILDER
- MYSQL WORKBENCH
- **❖** PHPMYADMIN
- ❖ JIRA
- **❖** TRELLO
- ❖ SLACK

CURRENTLY FOLLOWING

- JAVA 19,18, 17 DOCS
- ❖ SPRING BOOT
- ❖ REACT

SOCIAL SKILLS

- LEADERSHIP
- **❖ TEAM WORK**
- **❖ DECISION MAKING**
- **❖** SELF CONFIDENCE
- **❖ FLEXIBILITY**
- **❖ STRATEGIC PLANING**
- ❖ COMMUNICATION SKILLS

LANGUAGES

❖ ENGLISH

Full professional proficiency

❖ SINHALA

Professional working proficiency

INTERESTS

- ❖ RESEARCHING
- ❖ SELF LEARNING
- **❖ TEACHING**
- ❖ RECRUITING
- TRAVELING & HIKING
- ❖ VIDEO GAMES
- **❖** READING
- **❖ COLLECTING STAMPS**

• XENON BAKERY POS (JUNE 2020 – JAN 2021)

XENON BAKERY POS is a commercial type Point of Sales System product introduced by Devzone for the Bakeries and Restaurants in Sri Lanka. The System consist with a Standalone Desktop Application using Java + Kotlin, MVVM with a spring boot server.

Contribution:

- Developed "Notification Manager" of the application.
- Contributed on Code Reviews of other Associate developers and Interns after being promoted as a Software Engineer.
- Contributed in Bug Ticket Resolving.
- Contributed and Developed Finance Management Function.
- Contributed in development of Stock and Inventory Management Function.
- Contributed and Developed Employee Management Function.
- Contributed in Application UI development with JavaFX

ZONE 365 (NOV 2018 – JUNE 2020)

ZONE 365 is a web application developed by Devzone to manage their own employees. This Application is developed with Php and Bootstrap.

Contribution:

- Contributed in binding restful web APIs to the application with the backend
- Contributed in frontend Development of the application

PROJECTS – AT UNIVERSITY

• FARMBUDDY - Research Project (FEB 2021 – SEP 2021)

FARMBUDDY is the final year research project which conducted to trace a farming crop's growth and guide user from selecting a right crop matching to area till plant it on a proper place and get the harvest. Developed with Flutter, Dart, Firebase, and Type Script for Cloud Functions on 3 Trier Architecture. On Github: github.com/MrLeanage/farm_buddy

HAIVY PASTRY SHOP- (JUNE 2021 – SEP 2021)

Haivy Pastry shop is a Point of Sale (POS) standalone Java Application designed with JavaFX and MySQL with MVVM in order to satisfy Client's requirements to serve his customers who visits the shop. On Github: github.com/MrLeanage/HAIVY-BMS

Book Mart Sales Buddy - (FEB 2021 – MARCH 2021)

Book Mart Sales Buddy in a standalone Java Client Server based application developed using RMI as server, JavaFX and MySQL to assist customers who visits the bookshop to find the places where books and other stationary items located in, check prices and offers by themselves. On Github: github.com/MrLeanage/SalesBuddyServer

Salinda Super (JUN 2018 – SEP 2018)

Salinda Super is a sample POS System developed for well famous Salinda Super supermarket network (targeted to shop on Ragama). System was designed with JavaFX and MySQL in order to meet the client's requirements. On Github: github.com/MrLeanage/SalindaSuper

PERSONAL INFO



🔀 GAMPAHA, SRI LANKA



(+94) 77 9211 001



uthpalaliyanage@yahoo.com



linkedin.com/in/mrleanage



github.com/MrLeanage



stackoverflow.com/users/154 56947/mrleanage



upwork.com/freelancers/~01 41fa2e1193210d98



twitter.com/MrLeanage

PROJECTS – TOP OUT SOURCED

I have developed more than 30 applications as out sourced projects for different Universities, personal and foreign clients and on Fiverr Since 2017. Here I have mentioned top recently completed projects. You can find more at Git Hub.

HAPPY PET - Research Project (FEB 2022 – NOV 2022)

Happy Pet is an out sourced final year research project which is designed and developed by myself for 4 students to trace skin diseases of pets and suggest home remedies. Developed mobile application with Flutter and backend with Python with Firebase on 3 Trier Architecture. Used NLP, AI Chat bots, Image Recognition with SVM. On Github: github.com/MrLeanage/happy pet mobile

Grievance Management System - Research Project (FEB 2021 - NOV 2021)

Grievance Management System (GMS) is a java based web application which was designed to Micro Cars (PVT) Ltd to manage their employee Grievances. Developed using Java, Web Sockets for java chatbot and MySQL with 3 Tier Architecture. On Github: github.com/MrLeanage/GMS

Mansek Stock Market Desktop Application (NOV 2020 – APRIL 2021)

Mansek Stock Market Desktop Application is a KotlinFX project of a Chinese & Indian firm called Imaginato which I handled via Upwork. There I have developed the Main UI components in order to work with APIs, Concurrency and Coroutine threads concepts. Application is designed on MVVM Architecture. In there I have worked as a team with their other employees with Agile Practices and tools.

EDUCATION



Graduated (FEB 2021 – SEP 2021)
1st Class BSc (Hons.) in Computer Science and Software Engineering.
Convocation in 2022 March

From University of Bedfordshire, United Kingdom. (Top Up at SLIIT)



• Higher National Diploma (HND) (SEP 2016 - NOV 2019)

From Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology (SLIIT)

REFFERENCES

• Mr. Uditha Silva

Senior Technologist / Co-Founder

Devzone Software Information Systems, Gampaha, Sri Lanka, 11000.

Tel: +94 77 079 8025

Email: uditha.s@devzone.lk

Mrs. Namalie Walgampaya

Senior Lecture (Department of Information Technology)

Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology (SLIIT), New Kandy Road, Malabe, Sri Lanka.

Tel: +94 11 754 4135 Email: namalie.w@sliitlk

Mrs. Disni Siyarathne

Senior Lecture (Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering) Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology (SLIIT), New Kandy Road, Malabe, Sri Lanka.

Tel: +94 71 561 8336 Email: disni.s@sliitlk